[Music]
All right away. Back there's
Can we start with the yesterday there
was a report that your contract with the
Bengals goes through 2027. Can you
confirm if that's true? And if so, the
organization decided not to announce it.
Do you know why the team decided not to
announce it a year after they announced
I I don't think it really matters. I I
coach every day like it's my last and
I've been through years in 2019, 2020
that were
literally you coach every game thinking
it could be your last game. And I've
seen how we responded after that. 21, 22
competing for division titles and
championships and
Um so this year is no different for me.
It's going through adversity. Coaching
every game in this profession like it
could be your last one.
Um I have a lot of confidence in our
staff that we're going to get this
turned around and we're going to finish
the season really strong and put
together a great plan to get back to
those championships I mentioned. So very
confident we can do all that. Just for
accuracy's sake though, it is through
2027. I'm I'm not going to respond to
that. I just told you I coach every day
like it's my last one. Wait, you don't
get a chance to talk to ownership or do
we don't get that opportunity. What kind
of assurances have you been given from
ownership?
>> talk every week. Every week you talk
about your contract or
>> Every week we talk about everything.
When was the last time you spoke about
your contract and the status? Um it's
not really part of our conversation.
It's every week we're just trying to
create together a great plan to win
football games
and make sure our team's ready to go,
make sure I'm ready to go. So
Um I know that's of interest to you
guys, but we're just focused on being
the Dolphins coach.
>> Is it fair to say that's reassessed
after the season every year? You'd have
to ask them.
Ask them. Yeah. And we don't get that
chance.
>> Okay. Well, I'm sorry.
Okay.
Just be I'm just being straightforward
that we would ask them, but we don't get
that opportunity.
>> Okay.
Tua going through protocol? Yeah, he's
still going through protocol.
Yeah, he'll be same as last week. He'll
go through practice today, went through
the walk-through.
Um but again, protocol so I'm not going
to make any guesses on where Tua ends
up. Is anyone else out this week?
Uh Christian Wilkins will be out for
sure. There There's some other guys
we'll work through the next couple days,
some of the ones we talked about the
other day. Um
but don't want to make any prediction on
where they end up, but Chris will be the
one that's out for sure. How's Amari?
Amari looks pretty good. So again, once
we get on the field, we'll assess these
guys better, but uh felt really good
about Amari coming out of yesterday. Was
there a conversation about him getting
back in the game at some point? Amari,
you see we didn't see him with the
trainers a ton. I mean, what was that
like as y'all went Um honestly don't
remember even at what point it happened
as we sit in now. Um
so just he was out at that time. Wasn't
a lot of conversation. We were just
trying to go score points. Does the
confidence that ownership has has shown
in you
give you the the peace of mind when
you're evaluating young players and
trying to rebuild the defense?
>> Yeah.
Here's what I try to do every day, make
the best decisions so we can win the
game. And a lot of that is trying to
strengthen your team and your roster
by giving opportunity guys like that
like we've done this season. So
I think if you're if you twofold, if
you're going to say, "Well, I'm going to
do things because this could No, I want
to do what's best for our team and our
program to win immediately, win long
term." And so that's every decision. If
if you're worried about losing your job
and that's how you're going to make your
decisions, you're not going to be very
effective with what you do. And um it's
been a disappointing year. We're not
going to run from that. I'm not going to
run from that. And the blame falls at my
feet, nobody else's truthfully. I got my
hands all over this thing. Um haven't
done a good enough job, I understand
that. But I also have seen how this
staff can respond and these players can
respond cuz we've been through this
before. This is very similar to to the
end of 2020. It felt very
bleak and it was discouraging and all we
did was turn around and respond with
back-to-back divisional championships
which is rare to do in this division,
play for conference championships, play
for Super Bowls. I feel extreme
confidence that we know how to do that,
we know how to get back to that. And
that's exactly what we're going to set
our mind to do. A big thing you guys did
in that off season after 2020, you go
get Trey, you go get multiple Yeah.
agents like that. Are you confident in
ownership given that Burrow's making
more, Jamar's making that they'll be
able to I'm confident that we're going
to make the best decisions for the
organization. It's I I got a ton of
belief in our coaching staff, our
scouting department, our ownership that
we are very much in alignment with every
decision we've ever made here. And so
again, if when things haven't been good
enough over the course of this season,
there's really no one to blame other
than me, truthfully. And so I know we
all play a a piece of this, but I'm the
guy that gets to sit there and talk to
the team every single week, present
plans and make in-game decisions and so
um frustrating that that I haven't done
a good enough job this year, but uh ton
of confidence and maybe it rings hollow
to everyone listening, but I know that
we've been here before and I've seen how
we can get out the other side and I'm
very confident we're going to get that
done. He's taken criticism certainly
publicly.
Why do you cuz I know you believe in
him. Why do you believe in
Because I've worked side by side with
him for for 7 years now and um have a
ton of confidence in how he sees things
and the vision he's got and the vision
that we have together.
Um our scouting our scouting staff does
a great job and it's it's rare that you
get a chance to have like a really
personal relationship with him and see
them and be on the same page and
communicate the way that we do. It's not
that way everywhere and so um I really
like the setup we have and and I think
it works well for us and it will work
really well for us going forward. What's
his overall feeling for all? Uh you'd
have to ask him. He's been He's been
great so far to my eye. We haven't got
on the field yet. Uh but again, when you
guys get that opportunity you can ask
him. Do you anticipate him practicing
today? Joe Burrow? Yeah. Yes, I do.
Christian, he had a very minor left foot
injury Okay. on Monday and I didn't know
what
that was. Nothing?
If you're monitoring that closely
especially now with the team out.
Looking at the roster, it's a very high
percentage of guys who have never played
in the playoffs here Yeah.
How have you had to adjust the way you
present, the things you teach
considering that so many guys just don't
know what that's like?
>> Yeah, a lot of it is
we've we've got a rhythm that
we think serves us well. Um we're never
afraid to modify anything over the
course of the week. We do that.
You do lean on the coaching staff who's
who's been in those games you mentioned.
We got a lot of players on our team that
have been in those games. Um and then
again, we we feel like we've accumulated
a lot of guys that have won whether it
just be at the college level if they're
new to our team.
And that's that's a big part of it. So
again, that hasn't gotten us where we
need to be this year, but um there's
certainly a winning attitude in the
locker room and guys understand what the
standard looks like and do a good job
holding each other to that. Has this
been a year where you've kind of felt
the kind of the story of the year has
been the youth and then you trying to
step up and do more and go through that
process?
>> Yeah, there there's an element of that
and there's always going to be years
where you find that, you know, where
you're trying to balance the vets you
have on the team and trying to really
bring along young players so that they
can presently be good players for you
and and continue to develop and you can
be in a good spot in the future. So
I feel like if you look at all six of
the rookies we got, we we put them all
out there and we got a chance to watch
them all play and grow and
um I think it's a really exciting class
and I know that we hit on all six of
them and I feel really good about it.
And so we'll just we'll just keep
building. When a team's out of playoff
contention, usually talk goes to maybe
developing younger players and and
focusing on that instead of maybe what
the mission was before. Why is that
maybe not a consideration for y'all?
>> We've played all six of our rookies, so.
Well, in terms of even just further down
the roster
trying to find everybody whether they're
rookies or not um instead of trying to I
think we're actively doing that. I think
we've we've tried to do that all season
and we'll continue to do it over these
next couple games. Howie told you Sunday
Monday was that
one way he would describe
uh DJ Turner is very driven. Yeah. He's
been climbing all the time especially
this season. Your thoughts on on DJ and
I know you've talked about his Pro Bowl
potential.
>> Yeah.
What are your thoughts on why he's done
so well Well, I I think again, he's in
his third year.
So he's had a chance to learn from two
years of experience of of the ups and
downs that you deal with in this
profession that you deal with playing
corner, you know, and going against all
the guys he's got to go against.
And so
I've often mentioned that the
conversation he and I had in training
camp, you know, coming out of training
camp when he was coming off of an injury
before week one and his response was
just consistent with all the work that
he's really put in over the summer. And
And so now there's just this extreme
consistency there. He's got a confidence
that comes with that. Like I really You
can see when a guy has earned it, the
confidence. There's a lot of guys that
can walk around with arrogance or
brashness because they're talented, but
the work ethic doesn't necessarily match
the talent that they have. DJ is a guy
whose confidence stems from the work
he's put in. And so we've all seen it as
players and coaches. And so to see him
go out there and play with the
consistency he has, um it makes you
really proud of him because a guy who's
just, "All right, I'm facing a little
bit of adversity. I'm not starting week
one. I was just told I'm not starting. I
think I should be." Um
didn't say anything about his teammates,
thought that they were very deserving
the opportunity they got. "I'm just
going to go work." And that's what he
did and he got his opportunity and he's
made the most of it. I think he's having
a Pro Bowl year. And so it just I I
think proud's the first word and not
that I I have anything to do I don't go
out there coach the corners. That's
Chuck, that's Anthony um that's Al and
everything that they're doing, but I am
proud just to know the person and the
response I've seen from him. That's
leadership. Like when you talk about
leadership, developing leadership, um it
doesn't always have to be loud and vocal
and all that stuff. Sometimes it can be
go out there and I'm just going to do my
job and make sure everyone knows I'm
dependable and they can count on me and
that's that's exactly who DJ Turner has
been this year. Captain potential?
Absolutely. Absolutely. I was thinking
about this. Go ahead, Butch.
Do you think Jamar has a shot this week
and before he got before he went, you
know, had his injury problems, what did
you see from him in I I saw a guy that
was fighting through injury, you know,
and and so I think he's just had a tough
go of it this season and and it's
because just things that have happened
to him on the field. And so I don't want
to make any declarations about this week
because we haven't got out there and
practiced yet. I want to make sure we
see him practice and he's got confidence
in that, we've got the confidence in
that before we put him back out there.
Um
so again, that's It's up in the air
really as we watch him go through the
week, but uh I I like he sits in the
front row of the team meetings, man.
He's He's all eyes on me when I'm up
there presenting. He does a great job
taking it all in. Jerry's office is
right next to mine. I you know, I can
see the attitude he's got every single
day, and
so I I'm fired up when when we do get
him out there, whether it's this week or
not, um
for the future that he's got here
because he's a guy that I'm really high
on. He seemed pretty active. I mean,
like in August. I mean Yeah. He didn't
have much of a you didn't have much of a
spring. You just seemed to be active
before you got hurt Yeah, and he was
healthy, you know, and then he still had
to fight through the injuries. That's
tough to evaluate any rookie when
they're fighting through injuries. We
had that last year with Chris. We had it
with McKinley. We had We had some guys
that just got dinged up during the
season, and they fight through it just
like Ja'Marr has done. And so I look
forward to getting him on the field and
letting him make an impact for us cuz I
know when he's healthy, he'll be able to
do that. I was thinking about this um
going back to Miami, and then you
mentioned lessons from 2019 and 2020. In
2019 in Miami, what did it end up
meaning the way Boyd like fought back to
the line of scrimmage in that one moment
when he was hurt, and and kind of you're
hoping to see some similar things down
the stretch here?
>> Yeah, it shows the heart and the
character of the guys we have that um
they just want to win, you know, you
tune out the outside noise, and you tune
out, you know, anybody making a comment
to you about the draft. None of that's
just nonsense. We put every second of
our livelihood into winning games and
and doing everything we can to represent
ourselves the right way.
And so these types of games are big
character games. You get a chance to
reveal what we're made of. You know, we
know we're not going to the playoffs. Uh
but you still get a chance to go out
there and fight like we did in 2019. And
you know, I remember Iffert picking up
TB on triple in and and helping him get
up, and we talked the ball, and then we
throw vertical for touchdown the next
play, and all this tape that we still
use today
um
is represented by those guys that
started this process for me. You know,
the TBs and the Geos of the world and
the CJs and the guys that fought to to
build the culture and the foundation
that we kept building on over all these
years, and we got the guys the guys in
the locker room are doing the same thing
right now. It is disappointing where
we're at, but we're still have a
foundation that we're going to continue
to build on, and so we can go win
divisional titles and conference titles
and Super Bowls in the future. Was there
a part of you like
when you met Joe like thank goodness we
we got out of Miami hopefully cuz we get
Joe at number one?
>> No. No, it's You couldn't look at it
like that. We again, that's just doing a
disservice to the work we put in every
single day. If you say oh, you want to
go lose a football like absolutely not.
That You don't I don't think people
really understand what the next morning
feels like for us when we lose a game.
What the bus ride feels like, what the
plane ride feels like, what getting up
the next day and doing whatever you got
to do and trying to get the guys going
again on a Wednesday, Thursday, Friday
to get ready to play on Sunday.
Um what it does to your fam None of
that. So, we fight every second to win
football games. We don't for 1 second um
tolerate anybody that says we should do
this or that and not focus on winning.
So,
um that's what I love. When I have a
team meeting this morning, and you just
look in their eyes, everybody's on the
same page. Everyone knows what's at
stake here. What's at stake is we need
to win the game so we feel better, and
so that we can build some momentum for
ourselves and then go win the next one
and then do things we got to do in the
off-season to keep improving our team.
But that that's our only focus right now
is finding a way to go down to Miami,
win the game, get on the bus and the
plane with a smile on our face because
it's been too too few of those this
year. Going back to what you were
talking about with the setup, and and
you talked about how much you love the
input you get to have with the scouts
and and the setup here. Yeah.
How willing is the organization and I
I'll ask this cuz you too, but since
you're a big part of the draft process,
is to look at
you guys had a lot of success that
you've talked about with that '21 and
'22 seasons, but the last couple of
seasons with them all ending in losing
seasons, how willing is everybody to
look at the process and maybe make
tweaks and changes to it if need be?
Yeah, I I think for a lot of the reasons
everything was praised in '21 and '22,
and then you have down years, and it's
okay, you need to change everything.
Well, where were those comments when we
were doing it very similarly, and we
were having a great year? So, for us
um
we everybody's always open to evolving.
I can't speak for everybody, but I know
just from dealing with everybody in this
building, everyone wants to win and do
everything it takes to win. And so
I know that better than anybody cuz I
interact with everybody. And so I feel
extreme confidence that we are all on
the same page. All we want to do is win
and bring championships here to
Cincinnati, and we'll do whatever it
takes. To put it in specific words on
how that's going to look, that's all for
us behind the scenes to work through it
and make sure we're we do all that, but
um I have absolute confidence that we
have the right people and the right
setups to make this happen because we've
proven it, and and we'll prove it again.
Do you believe ownership in the front
office feels the same way about you? I I
I don't want to speak for anybody, and I
get what Mike just said, but
I have a great relationship with them. I
believe in them. Um I don't ever want to
speak for someone when they're speaking
about me. That's that's unfair. I
shouldn't do that, but um I love the
relationship I have with everyone in
this building. The unique thing about
this is we get to meet so often, and
that's a really good thing because
there's no 3 weeks of no communication
face-to-face. So, I'm wondering what
what they think about a game, what they
think about a None of that. We We get a
chance to form a relationship and go
through all this stuff, and it's the
right way to do it. And And so again,
I'm I'm excited for
to finish out this season the right way
and for the future as well. It looks
like Miami made a change at starting
quarterback. Looks like they're going
with Skylar Thompson. What's your
overall take? I I haven't seen that. I
mean, I know that was reported. I
haven't heard Mike McDaniel say that.
So, until that um they've got a really
good offense. I think that Mike does a
great job with the scheme.
Um
I don't want to call it unique cuz we
we've seen it over the years with with
him in different places, but he does a
really good job being creative and
stressing you in different ways maybe
that some other teams don't in the run
game, and
um not afraid to to be very creative
with how he does it. And so got a lot of
respect for Mike McDaniel and the job he
does, and
um I know they they ran into some
circumstances in Pittsburgh in cold
weather, and that's that's a good team.
Um but it it's a it's a very difficult
offense regardless of who the
quarterback is. They They put a lot of
stress on you in the run game. They do a
great job getting guys open with a lot
of speed in the pass game that can
finish on explosive plays, and so it's a
very challenging group to go against.
You drafted a quarterback in a while, um
even in late rounds. Has that This year
was that a consideration at all? I know
y'all swapped through the QB 3
a lot this off-season. Was it a
consideration to maybe see what you
could get in the seventh? We always
evaluate. You know, we always evaluate
who's out there and how they fit us.
Um
Put up against another position, put up
against our quarterback room, and
um
obviously we've we've done what we've
done. Zac, when you I know your focus
obviously is on winning the game in
front of you, but with three games left,
what do you want to see out of guys that
are you know, maybe outside of the core
guys that you have that when you when
you and Duke go at the end of the season
starting evaluating and figure out what
you need to do for 2026, what can guys
show in these last three games to show
that they should be part of what you
guys part of part of the plan before you
guys figure out what you need to add or
improve on the team to get back to where
you are? Continue on the same trajectory
a lot of these guys are on. You know, I
think with with
any player at the beginning of their
career, um guys that have gone on the
field for us have have truly you can
truthfully say gotten better every
single game. And so just continue on
with that, and all the work that these
guys have put in over the course of
their careers, but really starting back
in January of getting putting together a
great off-season, all the work they put
in the summer, training camp, going
through the season. Like it's You don't
stop now just because of the
circumstances we're in. So, um I expect
these guys to continue to give their
best. I know they will. And to your
question, what do young guys You just
want to see them continue on the same
trajectory we've seen them on, um
especially these last couple weeks.
All right, thank you. Thanks, Zac.